Daniel Filipe Nunes Silva communication systems enginees



PERSONAL INFO

Website

danielementary.me

Email

danielementary@proton.me

Phone Number

+41 76 545 00 24

Location

Fribourg, Switzerland

PERSONALITY

Traits

Honesty Critical Thinking

Enthusiasm

Interests

Specialty Coffee Watchmaking Formula 1

ABOUT ME

I am a communication systems engineer specialized in cybersecurity. Facing new challenges, learning modern technologies, and working on hands-on projects motivate me. I aim to enable positive change in our digital world using my skills in security and privacy.

EDUCATION

MSc in Communication Systems at EPFL

2019-2022

Strong background in cryptography, software and information security, formal verification, and interest in image processing and machine learning

BSc in Communication Systems at EPFL

2016-2019

Strong background in mathematics, information theory, algorithms, and interest in visual computing and data science

EXPERIENCE

Cryptography Intern at Nym Technologies SA SEP. 2021-MAR. 2022

Design and implement Rust applications for the Nym network leveraging attribute-based credentials and zero-knowledge proofs

Software Developer at PROGIN SA

SUMMER 2020

Develop a dedicated construction cost estimating software in C# and a SQL database suiting the specific needs of the company

Research Intern at Kudelski Security

SUMMER 2019

Build a proof of concept for the FENTEC project by extending FFmpeg C source code to perform motion detection on encrypted video streams

Low-Voltage Systems Developer at EPFLRT

FEB. 2019-MAR. 2020

Integrate several sensors in EPFL's Formula Student racing car in collaboration with the different divisions to allow data acquisition

PROJECTS

Formally Verified Prefix-Free Codes

Implement a prefix-free encoder-decoder pair in Scala and formally prove the implementation for correctness using the Stainless framework

Zero-Knowledge Circuit Evaluation

Implement the ZKB++ protocol featuring KKW preprocessing, which enables privacy-preserving computations, in Go and using the Lattigo library

Software Security Labs

Practice code audit, unit testing, and fuzzing. Play CTFs such as exploitation, reverse engineering, and forensics

COMPETENCIES

Programming

Python, Go, Rust, C, C#, Java, SQL Scala, Stainless, Coq

Linux, Shell Scripting, Git, Vim

Competitions

Google Hash Code 2018, 2019 and 2021

LauzHack 2018

EPFL Santa's Algorithmic Challenge 2017 Swiss Olympiad in Informatics 2016

Interpersonal Skills

Collaboration
Adaptability
Active Listening

Languages

French Native
Portuguese Native
English C1
German B2